A Finding Aid to the Bernard Harper Friedman papers,1926-2011, bulk 1943-2010, in the Archives of American Art AAA.friebern
Archives of American Art
- Writings, 1940s-2010; Series 4; 8 Linear feet Boxes 16-23
  - By B. H. Friedman, 1940s-2010 (Box 16)
    - Manuscripts and Drafts (Box 16)
      - "Mushrooms: A Field Guide to the Harvard Drug Scandal", circa 1963 (Box 18, Folder 14-15)
      - My Case Rests (other versions titled The Kelptomaniac and "Things"), circa 2004 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - My Small Self: A Play in Ten Scenes (another version is titled In Search of Luigi Pirandello: A Play in Two Acts), circa 1997-circa 1999 (Box 18, Folder 17-19)
      - Notebooks, circa 1940s-circa 1950s (Box 18, Folder 20-21)
      - Notes and Fragments, undated; 1986-1988 (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Open End (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - "The Ossorio Collection", circa 1967 (Box 18, Folder 24)
      - "Parkhurst Tower", circa 1980s-circa 2000s (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
      - "Past Imperfect", circa 1985-circa 2000s (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Planning a Trip: A One Act Play, circa 1995 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Poems, circa 1950s-circa 2000s (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - "Pop Goes the Dandy", circa 1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - "The Price for a Piece of Paradise", circa 1968 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - "Raw Art", circa 1990s (Box 19, Folder 12-17)
      - "Rendering of an Architect", circa 1961-circa 1973 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - "Scenes Arranged by Hope and Chance" (Box 19, Folder 19-22)
      - Sex and Character - Novel (other versions titled Eros and Psyche, circa 2000-circa 2005 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Sex and Character - Play with comments by Alan Wynroth, director (another version is titled Eros and Psyche), circa 2000s (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
      - Short Stories, circa 1940s-circa 2000s (Box 20, Folder 4-14)
      - Short Stories List, circa 1940s-circa 1980s (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - "The Sleeping Pill", circa 1953 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - "Small Strokes", circa 1958-circa 1973 (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - Student Writings, Cornell University, circa 1943-circa 1948 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Swindle Sweetly: A Musical Farce, circa 1993 (Box 20, Folder 19)
        Music and lyrics by Michael Mooney from Friedman's book of the same title, based on The Alchemis t by Ben Johnson
      - "Tattoo", 1960s (Box 20, Folder 20-23)
      - "Things" Short Story Collection (other versions titled The Kleptomaniac and My Case Rests), circa 1970-circa 2000s (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - "Things" Story Version (other versiosns titled The Kleptomaniac and My Case Rests), circa 1980s-circa 2000s (Box 20, Folder 25-26)
      - "Two-Part Invention" (also titled "Flora's Two-Part Invention"), circa 2008 (Box 20, Folder 27)
      - [Untitled (superseded by "When Everyone Hated the Jews")], circa 1993-circa 2000s (Box 21, Folder 1-7)
      - "Virginal Triptych", circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Weininger Essay, "A Touch of the Genius", 1946-circa 2000s (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - "When Everyone Hated the Jews", circa 1993-circa 2000s (Box 21, Folder 10-12)
      - Whispers - Novel, circa 1959-circa 1973 (Box 21, Folder 13-15)
      - Whispers - Play Adaptation by Alan Wynroth, circa 1973 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - "Who's Who" (another version is titled Diptych: Who's Who), circa 1953-circa 1970s (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Yarborough, circa 1962 (Box 21, Folder 19-21)
    - Published Versions (Box 22)
      - Articles, Reviews, Letters to the Editor, 1940s-2000s (Box 22, Folder 1-12)
      - Books (Box 22)
        - Almost a Life, Viking Press,Inc., New York, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 13)
        - Between the Flags: Uncollected Stories,1948-1990, Fiction Collective Two, Boulder, CO, Normal, IL, Brooklyn, NY (Box 22, Folder 14)
        - Circles, Fleet Publishing Corporation, New York, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 15)
        - Coming Close: A Novella and Three Stories as Alternative Autobiographies, Fiction Collective, New York, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 16)
        - Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney (Flora Miller Irving, research collaborator), Doubleday and Company, Inc., New York, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 17)
        - Jackson Pollock: Energy Made Visible, Da Capo Press, New York, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 1)
        - Museum, Fiction Collective, New York, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 2)
        - Swimming Laps: Stories and Meditations, Edgewise, New York, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 3)
        - Tripping: A Memoir, Provincetown Arts Press, Provincetown, MA, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 4)
        - Whispers, Ithaca House, Ithaca, NY, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Plays, Heart of a Boy, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Plays, My Case Rests, 2009 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Poems, Provincetown Poets, volume 1, number 2, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Short Stories, Miscellaneous (photocopies), circa 1970s-1980 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Lectures and Panel Discussions (Binder 23)
      - B. H. Friedman and John Ash introduced by Jull Hoffmann, 1987 November 13; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - "The Museum as Art Dealer," a Discussion about the Metropolitan Museum of Art and its Policy of Selling from the Collection, 1973 January 22; 1 sound reel, 1 sound cassette (VHS) (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - P.M. East, "Buildings in New York", 1961 September 6; 1 sound reel, 1 sound cassette (VHS) (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - "Pollock and Krasner," Pollock-Krasner House and Study Center 1989 Summer Lecture Series, 1989 July 30; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - By Other Authors, circa 1950s-circa 1990s (Box 23)
    - Cage, John. "James Joyce, Marcel Duchamp, Erik Satie: an Alphabet", 1982 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Henry, W. B. The Smallest Sound, Screenplay; B. H. Friedman Script Editor, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Schueler, Jon. "Fourty (sic)-Five Paintings", circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Schueler, Jon. "Magda/Death and the Margaret Ann/Magda and the Margaret Ann/the Sound of Sleat", 1970 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Schueler, Jon. "The Woman in the Sky," Excerpts (1958-1977), circa 1990s (Box 23, Folder 18)
- Diaries, 1948-1993; Series 5; 1.75 Linear feet Boxes 24-25
  In addition to recording personal and professional activities, Friedman's diaries (41 volumes) contain observations, overheard comments, and ideas probably intended for use in his writings. Typescript excerpts of varying lengths are from volumes 1-8 and 18-27.
  Diaries are arranged chronologically; typescripts of excerpts follow.
  - Volume 1, 1948 Spring-1949 circa January (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Volume 2, 1949 February-1951 circa June (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Volume 3, 1951 July - 1953 circa December (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Volume 4, 1954 January 25 - 1955 September 10 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Volume 5, 1955 October 23 - 1956 February 6 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Volume 6, 1956 February 13 - 1956 September 22 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Volume 7, 1956 September 28 - 1957 April 29 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Volume 8, 1957 April 29 -1957 September 7 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Volume 9, 1957 September 8 - 1957 September 13 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Volume 10, 1957 September 13 -1958 January 16 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Volume 11, 1958 January 18 - 1958 February 20 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Volume 12, 1958 March 2 - 1958 April 5 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Volume 13, 1958 April 1 - 1958 May 18 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Volume 14, 1958 May 18 - 1958 June 25 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Volume 15, 1958 June 27 - 1958 July 29 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Volume 16, 1958 August 1 - 1958 October 5 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Volume 17, 1958 October 15 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Volume 18, 1958 October 18 - 1959 January 7 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Volume 19, 1959 January 10 - 1959 February 6 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Volume 20, 1959 February 7 - 1959 May 10 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Volume 21, 1959 June 1 - 1959 September 1 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Volume 22, 1959 September 8 - 1959 November 23 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Volume 23, 1959 November 24 - 1960 April 2 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Volume 24, 1960 April 10 - 1960 November 19 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Volume 25, 1960 November 27 - 1961 January 22 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Volume 26, 1961 January 24 - 1961 April 23 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Volume 27, 1961 April 30 - 1961 July 9 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Volume 28, 1961 July 13 - 1961 December 19 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Volume 29, 1961 December 23 - 1962 February 23 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Volume 30, 1962 March 7 - 1962 May 9 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Volume 31, 1962 May 10 - 1962 June 7 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Volume 32, 1962 June 10 - 1962 August 12 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Volume 33, 1962 August 14 - 1962 October 27 (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Volume 34, 1962 October 24 - 1962 December 23 (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Volume 35, 1962 December 24 - 1963 February 17 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Volume 36, 1963 February 18 - 1963 June 23 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Volume 37, Dismantled, 1964 July 25 - 1968 April 9 (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
  - Volume 38, Dismantled, 1968 April 16 - 1972 October 27 (Box 25, Folder 5-6)
  - Volume 39 Dismantled, 1972 November 9 - 1978 November 16 (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
  - Volume 40, Dismantled, 1978 November 22 - 1988 April 19 (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
  - Volume 41, Dismantled, 1988 April 28 - 1993 April 14 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Excerpts from Volumes 1-8 (1948 Spring - 1957 May 17), circa 1964-circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 12-13)
  - Excerpts from Volumes 16-32 (1958 October 18-1962 August 12), circa 1964-circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 14-15)
  - Excerpts from Volumes 22-37 (1962 August 14 - 1964 July 24), circa 1964-circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 16-17)
- Subject Files, 1940-2010; Series 6; 4.45 Linear feet Boxes 25-30
  Subject files document Friedman's personal and professional interests, projects, and relationships. They contain correspondence, printed material, writings, and photogaphs in varying combinations; some items are photocopies. A small number of subject files contain video and sound recordings, as noted in the container list.
  - "Art World Details", 1996-1999 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - "Boo!", 2009-2010 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Circles Publicity, etc., 1961-1962 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Aaron Copland, 1978-2000 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Joseph Cornell, 1975-1982 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Elaine de Kooning, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Willem de Kooning, 1986-2004 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - "Dust Jacket Photos", 1977 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - East Hampton (Box 26)
    - Plans and Programs, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Home Sweet Home Moving and Storage Co., 1981 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. George Lamb Agency, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Surveys, Certificate of Occupancy, and Fire Underwriter, 1980-1983 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Specifications for 21-22 Georgica Close Road, circa 1980-1983 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Eros and Psyche, 1980-2001 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Morton Feldman Writings (Box 26)
    - Barbara Monk Feldman, 1996-2000 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Give My Regards to Eighth Street: Collected Writings of Morton Feldman, edited by B. H. Friedman, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Steve Johnson, 1994-1999 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Richard Kostelanetz, 1996-1998 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - David McKee, 1996-1999 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1996-2000 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - New York Studio School and SUNY Buffalo, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Raphael Mostel, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Permissions, 1996-2000 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Permissions, VAGA, 1997-1999 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Publicity, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Schirmer Books, 1997-1998 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Walter Zimmerman, 1996-2000 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Gutai Group, 1957-2009 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Heart of A Boy, 1991-2001 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Hilton Hotel, Rockefeller Center, 1961-1962 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Edward Hopper, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Ray Johnson, 1962-1978 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Steve Katz, 1978-2008 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Weldon Kees, 1988-2003 (Box 26, Folder 26-27)
  - Franz Kline, 1970-1990s (Box 26, Folder 28-30)
  - Lee Krasner, 2006-2007 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Timothy Leary, 1961-2005 (Box 26, Folder 32-35)
  - Timothy Leary (Box 27)
    - Correspondence with Chris Busa and Susanna Ralli, 2005-2007 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1963-2008 (Box 27, Folder 2-3)
    - Pamphlets, Newsletters, etc., 1963 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Michael Lekakis, 1960s-1980s (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Loans to Museums (Box 27)
    - ACA Galleries - Boston University, 1966-2006 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Castelli - Guggenheim Museum, 1964-1998 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Guild Hall - Musuem of Contemporary Art, 1963-1980 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Museum of Modern Art - Whitechapel Art Gallery, 1967-1997 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1963-1996 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Norman Mailer, 1960-2010 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - "Meeting the Maker", 1994-1997 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - My Case Rests (Box 27)
    - Chris Busa, 2008-2009 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Harold Evans, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Irene Lipton, 2008-2009 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Publicity, 2007-2009 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Susanna Ralli, 2007-2009 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Alfonso Ossorio (Box 27)
    - Notes, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - "Ossorio", undated; Includes 1 videocassette: VHS (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Jackson Pollock Correspondence (1950-1952), circa 1960s-1970s (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Printed Material, 1958-1974 (Box 27, Folder 21-22)
    - Clyfford Still Correspondence (1952-1955), circa 1970 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - "Planning a Trip", 1995 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Jackson Pollock (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1975 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Documents, 1970-1995 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Easthampton Free Library, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Entry for Dictionary of American Biography, 1976-1979 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Joseph L. Henderson and C. L. Syuph, 1969-1971 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Life Interviews (1949-1959), 1971 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Steven W. Naifeh, 1989-2008 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Notes, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Permissions, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Jackson Pollock: Energy Made Visible, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - "Jackson Pollock: The Psychoanalytical Drawings" by C. H. Wysuph, circa 1968 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Jackson Pollock and Lee Krasner Pollock, 1980-1984 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Research, 1940s-2000s (Box 28, Folder 14-16)
    - Time, 1950s (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Time-Life Books, 1968-1991 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Lee Krasner Pollock, 1958-1970 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - The Polygamist (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Rorschach, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Lillian Ross, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - "Roundtrip", 1980s (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Sapolin, 1979-1980 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Salvatore Scarpitta, 1969-2010 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - School of New York: Some Younger Artists, 1960-1994 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Jon Schueler, 1970-1996; Includes 2 sound cassettes. (Box 28, Folder 27-28)
  - Summer Solstice Theatre Conference, 1984-1990 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Theater (Box 28)
    - Abingdon Theatre Co., 2000-2007 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Bay Street Theatre, 1992-2000; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Beauty Business, 1987-1993 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Case History, 1987-1995 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - The Critic, 1986-1990 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Married Moments, 2000-2008 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - My Small Self, 1983-1999 (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
    - Alan Wynroth, 1997-2000 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Thread Waxing Space, 1992-1997 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - "To Gillian on her 37th Birthday", 1992-1997 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Travel (Box 29)
    - Barge, French Country Waterways, Ltd., 1999 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Cuba, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Egypt, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - India, 1991-1993 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Morocco, 1997-1998 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Paris (50th Anniversary '98) and France, 1991-1998 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Stockholm, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Tripping Permissions, 2002-2005 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Tripping Research, 2002 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Uris Building Corporation, 1963-2005; Includes 1 CD. (Box 29, Folder 16-17)
  - Esteban Vicente, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - "When Everyone Hated the Jews", 1995-1997 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Whispers (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1968-2010 (Box 29, Folder 22-29)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, Committee on Collections, 1975-1977 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, Review Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - The Writers Community, 1983-1985 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Printed Material, 1954-2010; Series 7; 0.2 Linear feet Box 30-31
  Most printed material is about or mentions B. H. Friedman and includes reviews and publicity for his published writings. Oversized items are posters announcing a symposium moderated by Friedman at Provincetown Art Association and Museum, and the Summer Solstice Theatre Conference's 1987 performance schedule that includes The Critic by B. H. Friedman.
  Additional printed material is found among correspondence (series 2), writings (series 4) subject files (series 6), and within the scrapbooks (series 8).
  - About or Mentioning Friedman, 1958-2010; Oversized material housed in Box 31 (Box 30, Folder 4-6)
  - Art and Poetry Related, 1975-1997 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Various Topics, undated; 1954-2002 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Printed Material About or Mentioning Friedman from Box 30, Folder 4, 1987; 1980 (Box 31)
- Scrapbooks, 1960-2006; Series 8; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 30-32
  Scrapbooks contain printed material - reviews, programs, invitaitons, announcements, calendars of events, press releases, etc. - publicizing Friedman's published writings and some of his activities. Some clippings are photocopies. Volume 5 includes a book proposal and photographs.
  - Volume 1, 1960-1978; Oversized material housed in Box 31 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Volume 2, 1965-1982; Oversized material housed in Box 32 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Volume 3, 1981-1991; Oversized material housed in Box 32 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Volume 4, 1990-2001 (Box 30, Folder 12-14)
  - Volume 5, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Oversized Scrapbook Volume 1, from Box 30, Folder 9, 1960-1978 (Box 31)
  - Oversized Scrapbook Volume 2, from Box 30, Folder 10, 1965-1982 (Box 32)
  - Oversized Scrapbook Volume 3, from Box 30, Folder 11, 1981-1991 (Box 32)
- Photographs, circa 1950s-2008; Series 9; 0.4 Linear feet Box 30
  Most photographs are of B. H. and Abby Friedman, friends, and family. Identified individuals include: Cary and Norman Bluhm, Sandy Friedman, Joellen Hall, Doug Heubler, Howard Kanovitz, Stanley Kunitz, Lee Krasner, Sheridan Lloyd, Annalee and Barnett Newman, Alfonso Ossorio, Magda Salversen, Salvatore Scarpitta, Jon Schueler, and Myron Stout. The Friedmans also appear in some group pictures with friends. Among the images of artwork are photographs of Jim Dine's 1979 portrait of B. H. Friedman and a color transparency of a Miró painting in the Friedman Collection. Miscellaneous subjects are a stack of books that includes Museum by Friedman, and a billboard. An album contains scenes from a 1979 production of Whispers.
  Photographs are grouped by subject - people, artwork, and miscellaneous subjects. Additional photographs are found as attachments to correspondence (series 1), among the subject files (series 6), and as illustrations for writings (series 4).
  - People (Box 30)
    - B. H. Friedman (photographers: Fenee De Kona, Norma Holt, Charles Schaefer, Bert Stern, and unidentified), circa 1960s-2008 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - B. H. Friedman (Renate Ponsold, photographer), 1980; 1972 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - B. H. and Abby Friedman (photographers: F. Klauber, Arthur Schwoger, and unidentified), 1960-circa 2008 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - B. H. and Abby Friedman with Others at Friedman Home (photographers: Marc Neuhof and unidentified), circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - B. H. Friedman Family, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Friends, including Artists, undated; circa 1950s-1998 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Groups, Unidentified, circa 1950s (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Artwork (Box 30)
    - By Jim Dine, Joellen Hall,and John Schueler (executed 1955-1070), circa 1955-circa 1980s (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Friedman Collection, le Papilion by Joan Miro (executed 1933), circa 1970s-circa 1990s (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1970s-circa 1980s (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Photograph Album, " Whispers, 1979" (Box 30, Folder 26)